Genelde bağımlılığı bu işaretlerle tanımlarız. Sayın bakalım sizde kaç tanesi var:
Typically, we define addiction by these signs. Play along and see how many you have:
Tehlikeli kullanım; araba sürerken veya riskli anlarda telefona bakmak,
Like hazardous use, using while driving or when it's dangerous,
Bozulan sosyal ilişkiler; kendini izole etmek ve çevrendeki insanlardan kopmak,
impaired social functioning, like isolating yourself or giving up on your social roles,
Telefon yokken gelen yoksunluk krizi, sürekli telefona aşerme dürtüsü,
having withdrawal from your phone, cravings for your phone,
Artan tolerans; ekran sürenizin sinsice tırmanması,
increased tolerance, like your screen time creeping up,
Kullanımı azaltmaya çalışıp bir türlü başaramamak,
trying to cut down on your use and being unable to,
Planladığınızdan saatlerce fazla ekrana gömülmek,
spending more time using than you initially anticipated,
ve telefon için hobilerinizden vazgeçmek.
and giving up your hobbies and interests to use.
İçinizden kaç kişi "Eyvah, bu tam olarak benim" hissini yaşadı?
How many of you have that "Oh, crap. That's me." feeling?
Kendinizde görmüyorsanız bile, etrafınızdaki kaç kişide bu işaretleri görüyorsunuz?
And if you don't see it in yourself, how many people around you do you see these signs in?